PERSONAL PROFILE

An ambitious front end developer with a passion for developing and designing for the web. More than 2 years commercial experience in a web developer role, and much more experience with web technologies outside of the workplace. Able to learn new technologies quickly and effectively to suit any kind of project. Strong desire to build upon my existing knowledge and further myself as well as contributing to a team of like-minded people.

KEY SKILLS

Main technical skills: CSS3/Sass, HTML5, JavaScript (Vanilla), jQuery, cross-browser compatibility and responsive/mobile design, Ansible.

Experience in using: PHP, React, SQL, R, MATLAB, Google Cloud

Web tools: Git, Figma, Photoshop

Content Management Systems: WordPress (theme and plugin development), Magento (theme

development)

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)

EXPERIENCE

E3D-Online October 2018 to present

Web Developer

- Responsive front end development using HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Magento2 and Wordpress PHP development (custom themes, plugins etc.)
- Managing my own and a medium sized team's web development work using devOps tools like GitLab
- Managing LAMP/LEMP server configurations and code deployments using automation tools like Ansible

E3D-Online October 2017 to October 2018

Digital Marketing Manager

- Managing multiple Magento/Wordpress CMS's
- Controlling and monitoring Google Ad campaigns

- Reporting on Key performance indicators from Google Analytics and visualising the data to help inform decisions
- Content creation for new products

EDUCATION

Lancaster University - Computer Science and Mathematics
October 2013 to July 2016
1st Class degree

Sawtry Community College - A-Levels

September 2011 - July 2013
Maths (A), Business(A), IT(B), Physics(C - at AS level)

INTERESTS

Travel: I have a love for visiting new places and experiencing different cultures. I spent a year in New Zealand working and travelling.

Football: Played for local and university teams; I captained my university college team which involves organising everything like squads and training.

Web development: I follow many Front End web development accounts on twitter and keep up with latest trends and new libraries etc.

3D printing - I own two 3D printers and also enjoy using CAD software to make my own custom parts for various projects, like my RC car

EXTRAS

See portfolio of some of my web development work ~ ryans1224.github.io